Shivani Giri

Software Developer

Infrastructure Engineer with 4+ years of working experience who loves to solve engineering problems. Well-versed in writing code to architecting solutions & strategies. Always prefer following DevOps pratices using open-source softwares with a passion to contribute back to community.



WORK EXPERIENCE

2018

SAP Labs, Bangalore, India

Site Reliability Engineer (May 2020 - Present)

SAP Cloud Platform is a region specific PaaS solution. It's maintained by multiple teams in a single Infrastructure as code repository

- · Resolved production issues e.g. Memory Leak, Slow DB writes, etc
- · Automated rotation of AWS IAM user key after 90 days via Terraform & CD
- Achieved High availability by rearchitecting stack for multi-zone deployment with Load Balancer provisioned via Terraform
- Reduced downtime by 75% by introducing automated RCA scripts in CI/CD pipeline which can be triggered during outages
- Eliminated toil by automating landscape update process via shell scripting which made it 85% faster and error free
- Implemented Mutual TLS to authenticate incoming metrics with auto creation & rotation of certificates via CI/CD pipeline
- Automated compile & release creation of repos by small Docker project
- Utilized CD pipeline to automatically rotate DB and Grafana credentials

Leveraged Knowledge in Git, Grafana, InfluxDB, Riemann, Telegraf, Bash

Performance Engineer (Mar 2020 - Present)

Optimizing and Benchmarking various solution hosted on Kubernetes

- · Derived optimum configuration of Fluent in EFK stack
- Optimized Cortex performance (Distributed database for Prometheus)

Tooling: K6, Docker, Prometheus, Grafana, Kubernetes, Jaeger

Software Engineer (Dec 2019 - Feb 2020)

Short lived team meant for evaluating Jaeger for Tracing support

- Architected the Deployment strategy for Jaeger as a Service in an orchestrated environment
- Integrated Jaeger into Observability Stack of SAP Cloud Platform via personal project

Tooling: Cassandra, Jaeger, Helm, Kubernetes, Golang

DevOps Engineer (May 2019 - April 2020)

- Architected the product to be cloud-native and collaborated with team to ensure that DevOps practices are being followed
- Developed branch agnostic CI/CD pipeline on Jenkins & Github Actions with vulnerabilities checks. Tooling: Github Actions, Jenkins

Full Stack Developer (May 2019 - Nov 2019)

- Created Backend APIs in NodeJS for various features in a product which helped customers to visualize on-prem landscape
- Did UX enhancements on frontend using SAP UI5 library

Linux System Engineer (Aug 2018 - April 2019)

A project dedicated to migrate SAP Netweaver On-Premise systems to GCP $\,$

- Migrated 25+ Systems. Team achieved target of 1000 systems by year end $\,$
- Automated installation of Netweaver system via Perl script

Tooling: rsync, CloudEndure, Perl, Bash

2016 GVC Systems, Noida, India

Intern (May 2016 - June 2016)

Software Developer for IoT based applications and products

- Developed E2E products for customer solving some of their daily problems
 e.g. Capture Vehicle Number in parking lot, Automatic Door Lock System,
 Dash Cam streaming video to Cloud.
- Technologies: Docker, MQTT, SpringBoot, Android, Image Recognition, Java
 Python

Contact

6

+91 8376 949 476



giri.shivani09@gmail.com



github.com/arpitjindal97



twitter.com/arpitjindal97



linkedin.com/in/arpitjindal97

0

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATIONS

2021

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (July 2021 - July 2024)

2017

Secured 2nd position in Inter College Quiz Competition (Feb 2017)

2015

Awarded 50% Scholarship in all Semesters



SKILLS

- · Kubernetes, Helm
- K6, JMeter
 - Prometheus, Fluent, Jaeger
- Docker
- Grafana, Kibana
- GitOps, IaC Jenkins, GH Actions
- Cortex, InfluxDB
- · Bash, Golang
- GCP, AWS



EDUCATION

2018

Master of Computer Applications (CGPA 8.53)

Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University (Aug 2018 - June 2021)

2015 (

Bachelor of Computer Applications (CGPA 7.52)

Amity University (July 2015 - June 2018)



OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Prometheus

Raised issue & followed through for the fix - Link

• Raspbian Recipes

Network related scripts - Link

Jaeger

Contributed to Helm Charts - Link

Jaeger Deployer

Deploy Multi-tenant Jaeger using K8s - Link

Activities on Github

Various PRs & Issues - Link



HOBBIES AND INTEREST

- Playing Games
- · Streaming Netflix
- Irregular GYM
- · Coded this file in Latex
- Listening to Music